Register of the Sidney Brooks papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Sidney Brooks papers
1925-1927
53009
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
The Sidney Brooks papers contain correspondence, mailing lists, reviews, synopses, and other materials relating to his book on American-German Relations after World War I, America and Germany, 1918-1925 (1925). The collection also includes a photograph of Sidney Brooks.
Brooks, Sidney, 1892-.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1953.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
1892 December 20 Born in New York City
1913 Graduated from Interlaken School, Rolling Prairie, Indiana
1917 Enlisted in U.S. Army with 19th Engineers, sailed to France
1919 Joined office of Allied Director of Relief in Paris, in charge of supply and distribution of food to Finland, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, and northwestern Russia.
1919 Awarded Varsovia Medal by the government of Poland.
1920-1923 Worked with Herbert Hoover in the American Relief Administration in Europe. Became member of managment and executive committees, chief of the Department of Records, Statistics and History, and founded and edited the American Relief Administration Review.
1924 Returned to United States.
1926-1932 Worked for International Telephone & Telegraph Co. as statistician and head of information bureau.
1933-1935 Served as director of Bureau of Economic Research for the Republican Senatorial and Congressional Committee.
1937 Returned to active duty with Army as assistant executive officer in the Central Records Office of the 2nd Corps Area.
1940 Became news officer for Civilian Conservation Corps.
1942 Appointed assistant vice-chairman of the War Production Board, Washington, D.C.
1944 April 15 Died in Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Sidney Brooks collection contains correspondence, mailing lists,memoranda, reviews, publicity materials, and other materials relating to his book on American-German Relations after World War I. The book, America and Germany, 1918-1925 (1925), discusses American aid efforts to Germany: why they were made, what purposes they served, and what difficulties were encountered. The book's preface, synposes, and some quotations are also included. This collection also includes a photograph of Sidney Brooks.
Arrangement Statement
The collection is organized into 3 series: America and Germany, 1918-1925 file; Clipping; and Photograph.
American Relief Administration.; Germany--Economic conditions.; Germany--Foreign relations--United States.; Germany--Politics and government--1918-1933.; International relief.; United States--Foreign relations--Germany.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Germany.
- America and Germany, 1918-1925 file, 1924-1927
  - Correspondence, 1924-1927
    - To and from Sidney Brooks, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - To and from other individuals, 1927 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Mailing Lists, 1925 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Memoranda, 1924 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Publicity materials, 1925 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Preface, 1925 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Reviews, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Quotations, 1925 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Synopses, 1925 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Miscellany, 1925 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- Clipping, 1926 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Photograph, 1925 (Box-folder 1: 12)